<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PKI | Eclipse Keyple</title><link>https://keyple.org/tag/pki/</link><atom:link href="https://keyple.org/tag/pki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>PKI</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://keyple.org/media/logo.svg</url><title>PKI</title><link>https://keyple.org/tag/pki/</link></image><item><title>Keyple supports Calypso Prime PKI cards!</title><link>https://keyple.org/post/pki-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://keyple.org/post/pki-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since April, Keyple supports sessions secured by public key cryptography on Calypso Prime PKI cards. This enables
strong authentication of both the card and the data read from it, without necessarily requiring a SAM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="keypop-apis-for-pki-based-ticketing-systems">Keypop APIs for PKI-based Ticketing Systems&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://keypop.org/apis/calypso-layer/calypso-card-api/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Keypop Calypso Card API&lt;/a> now includes features for
managing Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) mode, offering integrators the flexibility to define any type of chain-of-trust
model for a PKI-based ticketing system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="extensible-certificate-format-support">Extensible Certificate Format Support&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Keyple libraries natively support the card (CardCert) and authority (CACert) certificate formats defined in the
Calypso Prime PKI specification. Moreover, they have been designed for easy extension to support any other
certificate format, ensuring seamless integration with various PKI implementations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="modular-cryptographic-processing">Modular Cryptographic Processing&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Like most other Keyple components, Keyple’s internal interfaces for managing cryptographic processing are designed as
separate libraries. This modular design allows for upgrades and modifications independent of Keyple-based ticketing
terminal applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For asymmetric cryptographic computations (ECC/RSA), Keyple provides a
&lt;a href="../../components/card-extensions/keyple-card-calypso-crypto-pki-lib/">specific library&lt;/a> using Java Runtime
Environment libraries and the open-source “Bouncy Castle” libraries. Ticketing integrators can also opt to use Keyple
Calypso Card extensions with their own cryptographic engine implementations, supporting any certificate format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keyple already supports such a scheme for secure card sessions with a SAM module and is prepared to seamlessly integrate
the future OpenSAM solution.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>