<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What is Eclipse Keyple® | Eclipse Keyple</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/</link><atom:link href="https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>What is Eclipse Keyple®</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020-2024 The Eclipse Keyple® project. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><image><url>https://keyple.org/media/logo.svg</url><title>What is Eclipse Keyple®</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/</link></image><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/overview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Coming from a rather closed technical environment, ticketing for transport is essentially based on proprietary solutions provided by manufacturers.
However, in order for the concept of Mobility as a Service to become a reality, and at a reasonable cost, the ecosystem should, as far as possible,
rely on open standards, APIs and SDKs as well as Open Source technologies. This openness has already been a reality for several years in the field
of passenger information and has enabled the explosion of rich and high-quality applications, thanks in particular to Open Data. Today, Eclipse
Keyple is paving the way for ticketing to follow the same path, by making available for free the first fully Open Source API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eclipse Keyple® accelerates the integration and development of ticketing applications by enabling multimodal transport services, public transport
operators and event organizers to implement ticketing and access control systems based on a common, open and modular base.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eclipse Keyple® works with Keyple&amp;rsquo;s extensions. The first available extension allows you to benefit from Calypso®'s main features of reliability,
security and interoperability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eclipse Keyple® transforms complex contactless ticketing, transportation and event access systems into a simple integration to manage terminal
readers and portals that use smart cards and mobile applications to enter and exit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an open source technology, Eclipse Keyple® offers uniformity of structure but does not lock you into a specific ticketing system. Plugins and
extensions are being created, or may be created by developers, to allow ticket processing integrating technologies other than Calypso®, based on
several programming languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why trust Eclipse Keyple®?</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/why-trust/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/why-trust/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eclipse Keyple® is an Eclipse open source project currently leaded by Calypso Networks Association, which has been the leader in contactless
electronic ticketing transportation standards since 2003.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3CWNho1rrSw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Free, easy-to-use and flexible&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Built by developers, for developers&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Tailored to public entities requirements&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Interoperable with any smart card reader solution (standard/proprietary, local/remote)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Open source libraries in Java and C++&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Audit and certification&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Compatible with any terminal architecture (mobile, embedded, server)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Developer-friendly, up-to-date documentation, code samples and how-to guides&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Permanent compliance to the latest Calypso® release&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Options for creating add-on features that incorporate Calypso’s advanced security together with non-Calypso smart cards for ticketing and payment&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Accredited and hosted by the Eclipse foundation&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Exchange platform between providers and transport authorities&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Help desk-Separate maintenance for software and equipment&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Online and offline trainings available that will help you get the most of Keyple&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Active on GitHub and within the Eclipse community&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Who is it for?</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/who-is-it-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/who-is-it-for/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whether you are a transport authority or operator, a mobility provider, a system integrator, an event manager, a mobility aggregator
or a multi-mobility startup, Eclipse Keyple® allows you to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reduce your costs and accelerate your developments.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Facilitate the integration of new services or technologies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use libraries to enable instant payments, remote top-ups, event and multimodal transport integrations, connection to park-and-ride services, and more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easily create applications or services compatible with existing card-centric or server-centric systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Benefit from a more diverse and easily collaborative network that encourages coopetition in a multimodal market: compete where you can, collaborate when necessary to create integrated mobility customer journeys.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Harness the flexibility to introduce modern, mobile and new architecture systems while maintaining integrations to legacy infrastructure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ensure the sustainability and future-proofing of your ticketing system, as Keyple is compatible with any smart card reader and SIO-enabled terminal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unchain from vendor lock in, black box and single provider systems to an open solution with access to multiple suppliers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enable partnerships with multimodal transport, building facilities including parking, tourism operators and events to offer seamless, single ticketing across the end customer’s journey.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>With Keyple Calypso extension:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Have easy access to a highly secure and interoperable standard, Calypso®.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quickly build new apps and integrations that conform to the Calypso® standard and other ticketing schemas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easily migrate from an existing, closed ticketing schemes to Calypso®, a high-end open ticketing, certified solution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Easily integrate with public transport providers that are using the Calypso® standard, today used in major cities around the world in over 25 countries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>What is Calypso®?</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/what-is-calypso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/what-is-calypso/</guid><description>&lt;p>Calypso® is a set of specifications describing a fast and secure off-line contactless transaction, between a portable object and a terminal.
It has been created for public transport ticketing at the end of the 1990s by some European public transport operators or authority
(RATP and SNCF in Paris and all France, STIB in Brussels, OTLIS in Lisbon, ACTV in Venice, Konstanz in Germany), in order to create an open,
interoperable and secure standard independent from industrials to ensure a real competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today Calypso® represents 20% of the world market of contactless smart ticketing in more than 25 countries and over 170 cities globally.
It brings to his user a guarantee of security and interoperability which relies on a total compliance with existing standards
(ISO 14443, ISO 7816-4, Global Platform). The Calypso® standard is managed by the Calypso Networks Association (CNA),
which is led by transports operators and public authorities in order to ensure openness and independence from industrials
in confront of other proprietary schemes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discover more about Calypso® here : &lt;a href="https://calypsonet.org/solutions-overview/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://calypsonet.org/solutions-overview/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keyple's main features</title><link>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/main-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://keyple.org/what-is-keyple/main-features/</guid><description>&lt;p>The goal of Eclipse Keyple® is to allow developers to easily implement fast and secure off-line contactless transactions
(using NFC cards, mobile phones, …) based on ticket processing integrating technologies other than Calypso® the Calypso standard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More specifically, Keyple is a set of open source libraries that will initially be available in Java and C++,
designed on the same mutual Object-Oriented Model compatible with any terminal architecture: mobile, embedded
or server and Interoperable with any smart card reader solution: standard or proprietary, local or remote.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To fully understand how Keyple works, it is important to discern two main components of contactless ticketing technology:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Smart Card Readers&lt;/strong>: Readers are situated at the entrance and exit of events, venues and transport sites.
For example, a smart card reader could be a terminal, a portable scanning laser gun, or a swipe tablet area that is embedded
into a door, vehicle or gate. Code is written for a terminal to set the parameters for allowing cards or apps to transmit
ticketing information data. Sometimes in a distributed architecture system design, the code for the reader is not on the
terminal, but in a cloud environment, so the reader sends the data to cloud-based architecture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ticketing application&lt;/strong>: This is behind-the-scenes code that is able to take the data from the smart card reader
and, in milliseconds real-time, analyze the balance of the ticket, confirm the permissions for entry, and update the data
on the ticket (for example, to confirm that the ticket holder can enter the gate or vehicle, and then to deduct the cost
of the journey and calculate the new balance).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>According to this scheme, Keyple defines two layers:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Smart Card readers&lt;/strong> are integrated through plugins implementing the SE Proxy API which manages the communications with
a smart card through any type of contactless or contact reader (local, remote, standard, proprietary…)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ticketing applications&lt;/strong> relies on a high-level Calypso® processing API to manage Calypso® commands &amp;amp; security features.
This API uses the SE Proxy API to communicate with the reader&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Keyple comes with dedicated plugins that integrate directly with smart card readers that have been built on standard
software interfaces including PC/SC, Android NFC reader, and Android OMAPI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In cases where there is a distributed architecture design, Keyple includes a Remote API plugin so that
a smart card terminal can be operated remotely, as if it were local to the terminal, and ensures that robust security and
speed is not sacrificed in a cloud-based system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Calypso Processing API is also available as a Keyple extension. This component carries out the terminal processing
element of ticketing technology. Access to Calypso’s security features are automatically managed by the Keyple extension.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>